https://www.charlesfaram.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Call our UK Office
+44 (0)1905 830734
Find Us
The Hop Store, Monksfield Lane, Newland, Worcestershire, WR13 5BB
English
USA (USA)
Canada (Canada)
Français (French)
Deutsch (German)
French Canadian (French Canadian)
Call our UK Office
+44 (0)1905 830734
English
USA (USA)
Canada (Canada)
Français (French)
Deutsch (German)
French Canadian (French Canadian)
Order
What Hop?
Order
What Hop?
Privacy Policy
The privacy policy is all about how we handle your data. Our privacy statement is different to the privacy policy as it is a lot more in depth. You can request a copy of the privacy policy and privacy statement at any time
Who are we?
Wellhopped Ltd is the parent company of the group containing Charles Faram & Co Ltd (UK), Hawkins & Floyd Ltd (UK), Charles Faram Inc. (USA). and Charles Faram Brewing Supplies Inc. (Canada).The group companies supply ingredients, products and advice to the drinks industry.
The Data Protection Manager can be contacted directly:
Email: dp@charlesfaram.comTelephone: (+44) 01905 830734
What personal data will we collect?
The personal data we would like to collect from/process on you is from the list shown below.   We will tell you explicitly at the point of collection which data we require, the lawful grounds for processing and the retention time:Personal data typeSourceNameData Subject or OtherAddressData Subject or OtherTelephone number(s)Data Subject or OtherEmail addressData Subject or OtherJob titleData Subject or OtherImageData SubjectSignature on contractData Subject
The personal data we collect will be used for the following purposes:
Provision and maintenance of contractCustomer contact to resolve issuesCustomer contact to plan and install installation or maintenance of productsData sharing between operational teams to assist in meeting customer requirementsComplaints investigation and resolutionPerformance and KPI data analysisInvoicing and contract financial management
Our legal basis for processing for the personal data:
To meet the contractual obligations entered into by you the client and the data subject.Purposes of legitimate interests pursued by the controllerProcessing is necessary to comply with the legal obligation of the controllerConsent given by you, the data subject
Legitimate interests
Any legitimate interests pursued by us, or third parties we use will be advised to you at the time we collect your personal data.
Consent
By accepting this privacy notice, you are giving us your permission to process your personal data specifically for the purposes identified.Consent is required for Wellhopped Ltd to process personal data where there is no overarching legal reason for the processing of personal data, but it must be freely given. Where we are asking you for sensitive data, we will always tell you why and how the information will be used.Where we are processing your personal data on the basis of consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time by following the procedure described in our document: Withdrawal of Consent Procedure.
Disclosure
Wellhopped Ltd will not pass on your personal data to third parties without first obtaining your consent, unless that is a necessary part of our processing procedure and we have advised you of that need at the point of the collection of the data.We may pass your personal data to the following third parties for the reasons shown below as part of the processing activities. Name of organisationLocationEU/Non EUSafeguards in place to protect your personal dataReasons for sharing dataHMRCEUGDPR compliantLegal obligations of the controllerFedexDPDWhite LogisticsFreightrouteJGS CouriersDavies TurnerDavies Turner Aircargo LtdAvon FreightDHLSchwartz logisticsABE TransportEU/Non-EUFulfilment of transportation servicesAdherence to GDPRDEFRA( Department for Environment, Food & Rural Affairs)APHA(Animal and Plant Health Agency)RPA(Rural Payments AgencyFDA(US Food & Drug Administration)EU/Non-EUCompliance with food safety standards and quality controlAdherence to GDPRWeyermann® MaltMurphy & SonTotally Natural SolutionsCastle MaltingRankin Brothers & SonsFermentisEUFulfilment of distributor servicesAdherence to GDPRChamber of CommerceEUFulfilment of servicesAdherence to GDPROak InnovationEUFulfilment of communications servicesAdherence to GDPRSalesforceNon-EUFulfilment of data storage servicesAdherence to GDPREOHEUFulfilment of data storage servicesAdherence to GDPRDatelEUFulfilment of IT servicesAdherence to GDPRGrant Thornton UK LLP and its associated firmsEU/Non-EUStatutory auditAdherence to GDPR
Retention of data
Wellhopped Ltd will process and store the personal data in accordance with the company retention period as detailed in the Retention Period Procedure.
Destruction of data
At the point that the company’s retention policy has determined that any personal data is to be deleted/destroyed, it is a requirement of the GDPR that removal of data is carried out securely. Wellhopped Ltd destroy personal data as follows:• Physical documentation is shredded internally once the purpose for which those documents were created is no longer relevant. Archive material is palletised, labelled as ‘Shredding’ and is collected by a contracted third party to be shredded securely.• Electronic data is deleted from the server location(s)
Your rights
At any point while we are in possession of or processing your personal data, you, the data subject, have the following rights:• Right of access – you have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you in line with the Subject Access Request procedure and using the Subject Access Request Form.• Right of rectification – you have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete.• Right to be forgotten – in certain circumstances you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records.• Right to restriction of processing – where certain conditions apply to have a right to restrict the processing.• Right of portability – you have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation.• Right to object – you have the right to object to certain types of processing such as direct marketing.• Right to object to automated processing, including profiling – you also have the right to be subject to the legal effects of automated processing or profiling.• Right to judicial review: if Wellhopped Ltd refuses your request under rights of access, we will provide you with a reason as to why. You have the right to complain as outlined below.All of the above requests will be forwarded on should there be a third party involved in the processing of your data.If you wish to exercise any of these rights, please contact the Data Protection Manager by email: dp@charlesfaram.com
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how your personal data is being processed by Charles Faram and Company Limited or by a third party as described above or about how a complaint has been handled, you have the right to complain to Charles Faram and Company Limited data protection representative, or to lodge a complaint directly with the supervisory authority.The details for these contacts are: Supervisory authority contact detailsData Protection Manager contact detailsContact nameInformation Commissioner’s OfficeCharlie GorhamAddress line 1Wycliffe HouseCharles Faram and Company LimitedAddress line 2Water LaneThe Hop Store, Monksfield LaneAddress line 3WilmslowNewlandAddress line 4CheshireWorcestershireAddress line 5SK9 5AFWR13 5BBEmailcasework@ico.org.ukdp@charlesfaram.comTelephone0303 123 111301905 830 734
Opt in. We don’t want you to miss anything….
Please use the form to indicate as to whether you are happy for us to hold and use any personal data which we hold about you. We will only use your information to send useful things like news, Faram’s features, event invitations, messages concerning hop contracts and communications related to business transactions.
H'opt in
READY TO ORDER?
Call: +44 (0)1905 830734 or Click here
About Us
Charles Faram has been established as merchants of hops and hop products for over 150 years. The company, which was originally based in Worcester, now resides in the small hamlet of Newland, situated at the foot of the picturesque Malvern Hills.
Download Our hop brochure
Latest News
Goodbye to Minstrel®
November 27, 2020
Written by Will Rogers, Group Technical Director Hop development takes many years, hard graft, and a brilliant understanding of how to encourage the very best
Read More »
CharMur launches fun and games for Christmas
November 26, 2020
First there was Brangelina… Now make way for #Charmur! All throughout this December @Charles Faram and @Murphy and Son (#Charmur!) will be working together to
Read More »
© 2018 Charles Faram Ltd | All rights reserved | Powered by LemonTop
